The isnan function, on line 20, checks to see if a
variable or expression is not a number and returns
true if that expression is indeed not a number and
false if the expression is a number. I will check
to see if x is not a number. Upon running this
code and the code on line 22, x is a number, so we
see the word False being returned and the result
of x times y. However, let's see what happens if I
change x to a float value that is not a number
and run this again. Not only are we told x is
not a number, but the calculation returns nan,
meaning not a number. Two key points to remember
here are isnan checks to see if a variable or
expression is not a number, and nan is a result,
not a function. As I change x back to 3, the next
math functions to cover are sqrt and isqrt, on
lines 24 and 26. Sqrt returns the square root of a
number. Isqrt? Let's figure that one out as we run
this code. We see the square root of 3, but what
do you think isqrt represents? In many of these
functions, I means integer, so isqrt returns the
integer of a square root of a number. On line 28,
which I will run next, the pow function returns a
number, raised to the power of another number. In
this case, we are raising y, -13, to the power
of x, 3, which should return a negative number
close to 2000. I was close as we see the result
of -2197. The last math function to cover is pi,
on line 30, which returns, you may have guessed,
pi, I will run this code, and we see the result
for pi. To use pi in a practical sense, the
area of a circle is pi times the radius squared,
so I will run this line of code, line 32,
which will calculate the area of a circle with
a radius of x, which is three, and the result is
28.27. The importance of knowing the math module
is its ease in solving complex math problems
related to statistics, geometry, trigonometry,
and other math problems without having to write
a lot of code. Practically, these math functions
can help with gaming apps, as many gaming apps
have math or statistics-based functionality.